## **Aman Kapoor**

⊕ 9990685184 | 
 □ a.kapoor1391@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/aman-kapoor-08294bb9/

### **Summary**

Data science professional using advanced & statistical analysis skills since 6 years to grow business profitably by generating insights and presenting with data visualization. Collaborating with people across the world to use machine learning skills and become "Master" on the world's #1 analytics hackathon platform.

### **Skills**

Technical Skills: Data Science, Machine Learning, NLP, Predictive modelling, Automations

Coding Languages: Python, Pyspark, SQL

Data Visualisation: PowerBI, Tableau, Excel Dashboarding

### **Work History**

### Dunnhumby Senior Applied Data Scientist

Jun 2021 to Present

- Managing data science team for NAM retailer. Responsible to manage project pipeline and mentoring team on developing new solutions.
- Built targeting strategies for new product launch, personalized rewards for multiple FMCG brands using Machine Learning, Statistical models and Predictive modelling.
- Calculating sales uplift for targeted campaigns using OLS models & Publishing performance dashboard for clients using powerBI. This reduced the measurement time per campaign by 2 hrs.
- Analyzed customer and support staff tweets for major NAM retailers using sentiment analysis and NLP. This helped create user satisfaction scoring and highlight focus areas for retailers.
- Created an algorithm to predict customer's lifestyle based on their shopping habits using statistical modelling and clustering techniques. Using these lifestyles in targeting strategies has given ~9% uplift in each campaign

# Cashkaro.com Assistant Manager- Analytics

Apr 2019 to Jun 2021

- Responsible for complete data and analytics setup for the company from preparing a data pipeline, creating business reports setup and automation of recursive tasks in each department using python, SQL and advanced analytics.
- Helped implement marketing and product strategies through real-time visualization reports & dashboards created using internal and 3rd party data on PowerBI and Excel
- Supported leadership in preparing company portfolio for investor funding by providing performance and finance data analysis and insights and creating reports for the same.
- Built Campaign Audience Selection tool using python which created 100 targeting audience in a single run. This
  completely removed redundant jobs of 2-3 marketing analysts.

• Create marketing channel performance dashboards by scraping API data in python and powerBI which helped increased average conversion rate of campaigns by 15%.

# Ernst & Young Consultant

Aug 2018 to Apr 2019

- Responsible for fraud analytics consulting solutions for multiple government sourced projects using python codes
- Data mining for text analytics, implementing fuzzy logics and identification of outlier data points in financial data to highlight red flags and facilitate the auditors to take further decisions.

### Paisabazaar.com Data Scientist

Mar 2017 to Aug 2018

- Automated performance reports for stakeholders of personal loan department using R and python. Also set cron jobs to automatically trigger multiple mailers which relaxed ~60% of analyst bandwidth.
- Created company portfolio for loans & cards to analyze customer behavior on our platform and marketplace using Tableau. This helped in strategy planning and increased lead conversion by 10%.
- Created regression models to predict the chances of personal loan approval for each customer. Implementation
  of this model helped customers make informed applications and increase approval rates by 12% and increase
  unassisted leads by 5%.

### **Education**

#### Post Graduate Diploma (Data Science)

Aegis School of Data Science

Feb-2017

#### **B-tech (Biotechnology)**

**SRM University** 

May-2015

### **Achievements**

- Won title of 'Competition Master' on Kaggle.
- Won 1 gold and 18 silver/bronze medals across multiple data science hackathons on Kaggle.
- Received Cashkaro Superstar award for outstanding performance for 3 quarters in a row.
- Won Swag and prizes across different hackathon platform.
- Volunteering as a torch bearer at Analytics Vidhya.